# WILLIAM N. TROUT

8013 JEFFERSON ST, KANSAS CITY, MO 64114

| 913-219-2425 |

Williamntrout@gmail.com

## **Profile**

Results driven Manager and with over twenty years of experience in the technology sales, service, team leadership/building, and operations compliance. Developed teams and processes that drive not only operational and compliance excellence, but also revenue growth and profitability. Known as a dedicated leader who facilitates a premiere customer experience and team orientated work environment that excels at sales, service, and operational goal attainment.

Developed talents and skills include:

- US Army Veteran
- Attention to Detail
- Goal Setting and Attainment
- Business Plan Development
- Responsible Leader
- Analytical Decision Maker
- Organized Planner
- Influential and Collaborative
- Process Development
- Problem Solver
- Leader Development
- Balancing Multiple Priorities

# **Professional Experience**

UMB Bank Oct 2019-Present

## **Branch Manager**

Independence, MO

- Leads the execution of all branch operas and revenue generating activities while following all bank regulations.
- Leads by example and coaches all associate on proactive financial conversations and digital migration.
- Implement and execute the retail strategy as set forth by company leadership and initiatives.

Bank of America, n.a.

Jan 2016-Sept 2019

# **Financial Center Manager**

Seattle,WA/Topeka.KS/Floating

- Conduct monthly audits of financial centers for Market Leader to identify operation and compliance issues and create plans to remedy those issues and create a culture of consistency regarding operations, compliance, sales, and client satisfaction. Co-ordinate/Orchestrate additional coverage for market as business demands.
- Develop close relationships with assigned business partners, such as Mortgage Loan Officers, Business Banking Officers to ensure that established goals for each business line are met.
- Manager/HR Functions, set priorities, direct and delegate sales responsibilities to the Relationship Manager(s), and ensure follow through on the completion/implementation of effective business plans acting as "Business Owner."
- Lead the team to attain sales/financial/compliance goals for the financial center, setting the example and tone for a strong, client centric, environment. Consistently meet and exceed profit, deposit, loan sales, client satisfaction, and operational excellence goals as defined by the Regional Manager, actively soliciting the various retail and Bank of America products and services.
- Works with staff and partners to implement digital banking transformation strategy and policy.

#### SPRINT CORPORATION

Jan 2015-Jan 2016

# National Retail Account Executive Seattle, WA

- Build and maintain excellent relationships with store managers and associates to help facilitate brand recognition and maximize revenue, reduce churn, and drive long-term customer engagement.
- Work with store leadership of several different locations to develop business cases focused on incorporation of carrier brand message and goals into individual store goals.
- Leverage relationships and partnerships with various teams in order to develop business plans and strategies in a rapidly changing business environment.
- Act as mobility brand ambassador to be the face of the company when conducting store visits.
- Ensure marketing initiatives are implemented and represented on partner sales floors across a large footprint.
- Maintain awareness and knowledge of competitor promotions and rate plans, and report back weekly findings in order to maintain competitive advantage.

BEST BUY Co., INC.

Apr 2014-Jan 2015

# **Best Buy Mobile Store Manager**

Seattle, WA

- Developed and implemented business plans designed to generate incremental revenue growth and profitability.
- Trained staff on all new product and service offerings in order to take advantage of an ever-changing marketplace.

• Oversaw and ensured that all standards were met and that all associates were working in a manner that generated long-term customer engagement, loyalty, and satisfaction.

## MOOREHEAD COMMUNICATIONS, INC.

## Verizon Store Manager

Sept 2013-Apr 2014 Seattle, WA

- Coached Sales Associates on sales behaviors to provide complete solutions to our customers and provide the best customer experience possible.
- Analyzed sales data to identify areas of opportunity that could be leveraged to drive overall team success and meet or exceed company goals and objectives.

#### NEBRASKA FURNITURE MART

Sept 2012-Aug 2013

## **Product Specialist/Home Theater**

Kansas City, KS

• Consultative sales of home theater products including Audio, Video, Accessories, Service Plans, and Install Services to ensure outstanding customer experience.

BEST BUY Co., INC.

July 2006-August 2012

# **Product Process Manager** (April 2011-August 2012)

Lawrence, KS

- Lead the 10 store district in performance as measured by the Store Excellence Audit: Scored 98.5% on retailing standards.
- Challenged the team to deliver the highest level of inventory integrity resulting in an annual inventory with only a \$500 total variance.

# **Customer Solutions Manager** (April 2009-April 2011)

Lawrence, KS/Oak Park, KS

- Coached Supervisors and Sales Associates on sales behaviors to provide complete solutions to our customers through consultative sales techniques.
- Analyzed sales data to identify areas of opportunity that could be leveraged to drive overall team success and meet or exceed company goals and objectives.

# Store Services Manager (December 2008-April 2009)

Oak Park, KS

- Coached associates from all departments to drive the sales of services and performance plans delivering services budget consistently and building a culture of success in this category.
- Demonstrated and coached sales behaviors of service plans and "Geek Squad" services improving performance throughout all departments with consultative sales coaching.

# **Merchandising Supervisor** (May 2007-December 2008)

Oak Park, KS

• Ensured all company merchandising standards were exceeded to provide a better customer experience.

## Magnolia Home Theater Sales Pro 4 (July 2006-May 2007)

Oak Park, KS

• Trained and mentored sales team on product knowledge and sales behaviors in order to drive sales and customer lovalty.

# TWEETER HOME ENTERTAINMENT GROUP

June 2003-June 2006

## **Store Operations Manager** (April 2005-June 2006)

Manassas, VA

- Responsible for total store operational functions including: opening and closing duties, transactional accuracy, cash handling, deposits, staffing, inventory, merchandising, and sales training.
- Functioned as primary store coach and trainer for all new hires as well as facilitating on-going training.

## Sales Specialist/In Home Specialist (July 2003-April 2005)

Fredericksburg, VA

• Trained and mentored inexperienced sales team to build store culture while personally developing the brand in the market through In-Home Consultative sales.

# THE GOOD GUYS

June 2000-June 2003

## Sales Specialist Audio/Video/Wireless

Escondido, CA

• Learned the fundamentals of sales and customer service, gained the skills to be the only store associates certified to work in all departments: Audio, Video, Car Audio, and Cellular.

## Military Service

**United States Army** 

A-7/8 FA

June 1992-June 1995

# **Education**

**Seattle University**